Guide to Baylor University Catalogs, etc. Cubb.00150
Cubberley Education Library
Baylor University
1890-1979
Cubberley Education Library
Cubb.00150
242 item(s) Catalogs for 1890/91, 1898/99-1899/1900, 1901/02-1903/04, 1905/06-1907/08, 1909/10, 1911/12, 1972/73 Preliminary Catalog/Supplement 1900 Announcements for 1913/14-1926/27, 1928/29-1946/47
Located in Waco, Texas. Founded in 1845 as a Baptist university in Independence, Texas. Coeducational until 1851. The women's division became Baylor College and moved to Belton, Texas in 1886 while the men's division relocated to Waco, Texas where it merged with Waco University. In 1925 Baylor Female college was renamed Baylor College for Women. In 1934 it became Mary Hardin-Baylor College. In 1971 it became fully coeducational and was renamed University of Mary Hardin-Baylor. In 1900 three doctors founded the University of Dallas Medical Dept. in Dallas, Texas which was acquired by Baylor University in 1903 and became Baylor College of Medicine located in Dallas. In 1943 it moved to Houston. In 1969 it became independent of Baylor but maintained close ties.
Texas; Women's colleges -- United States
- Baylor College (Belton, Texas), 1892-1931; 2 item(s) Catalogs for 1892/93 & 1930/31
- Mary Hardin-Baylor College, 1946-1947; 1 item(s) Catalog for 1946/47
- Baylor University Summer Quarter/Teachers Summer Normal, 1908-1920; 10 item(s) Catalogs for 1908, 1910-1915, 1918-1920
- Baylor University Summer Session, 1958-1963; 3 item(s) Bulletins for 1958, 1962, 1963
- Baylor University President's Report, 1903-1916; 10 item(s) Reports for 1903, 1908-1916
- Baylor University College of Medicine and College of Pharmacy, 1915-1916; 1 item(s) Announcements for 1915/16
- Baylor University College of Medicine (Dallas), 1916-1943; 34 item(s) Announcements for 1916/17-1917/18, 1919/20-1942/43
  Medical colleges
- Baylor University College of Medicine (Houston), 1947-1957; 8 item(s) Announcements for 1947/48-1955/57
  - Baylor University College of Medicine, Dept. of Pharmacology, 1968-1970; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1968/70
- Baylor Bulletin--essays including inaugural address, November, 1902; 1 item(s)
- Baylor University Bulletin, April 1904; 1 item(s) Collection of essays for 1904
- Baylor University College of Dentistry (Dallas), 1925-1926; 1 item(s) Announcements for 1925/26
- Baylor University Graduate Work, December, 1925; 1 item(s) Report for December, 1925
- Baylor Theological Seminary, October, 1905; 1 item(s) Announcement for October, 1905
  Theological seminaries
- Baylor Bulletin General Information, 1948-1969; 18 item(s) Announcements for 1948/49-1957/58. 1959/60-1966/67, 1968/69
- Baylor University School of Law, 1947-1967; 12 item(s) Bulletins for 1947/48-1948/49, 1950/51-1952/53, 1954/56-1958/59, 1960/61-1961/62, 1966/67
  Law schools
- Baylor University Arts and Sciences, 1948-1977; 19 item(s) Announcements for 1948/49-1955/56, 1957/58-1958/59, 1960/61-1966/67, 1970/71, 1976/77
- Baylor University School of Business, 1948-1979; 18 item(s) Bulletins for 1948/49-1952/53, 1954/56-1958/59, 1960/61-1964/65, 1966/67, 1970/71, 1977/78-1978/79
  Business schools
  - Baylor Business Studies, September, 1960; 1 item(s) Two essays.
- Baylor University School of Education, 1948-1971; 14 item(s) Bulletins for 1948/49-1949/50, 1951/52, 1954/55-1955/56, 1957/58-1958/59, 1960/61-1963/64, 1965/66-1966/67, 1970/71
  Teachers colleges
- Baylor University School of Music, 1948-1971; 11 item(s) Bulletin for 1948/49, 1951/52-1952/53, 1955/56-1956/57, 1961/62-1963/64, 1965/66, 1967/68, 1970/71
  Music in universities and colleges
- Baylor University Graduate School, 1948-1977; 16 item(s) Bulletins for 1948/49-1949/50, 1952/53, 1954/56-1958/59, 1960/61, 1962/63-1966/67, 1968/69, 1970/71, 1976/77
- Baylor University School of Nursing, 1951-1971; 10 item(s) Bulletins for 1951/52, 1953/54-1954/55, 1956/57, 1958/59, 1961/62, 1963/64, 1965/66-1966/67, 1970/71
  Nursing schools
- Baylor University Engineering, 1955; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1955
  Engineering schools
- Baylor University Engineering Studies and Forestry, 1958-1962; 2 item(s) Bulletins for 1958/60-1960/62